

Soohwan Kim

ALRESEARCH ENGINEER · SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

6-10, Seokye-ro 13-gil, Nowon-gu, Seoul, Rep. of KOREA

□ (+82) 10-4564-4668 | 🗷 kaki.brain@kakaobrain.com | 🏕 blog.naver.com/sooftware | 🖸 sooftware | 🛅 Soo-hwan

"Human-Machine Interaction Technology Researcher"

Summary.

Current AI Research Engineer at Kakao Brain. I majored in Electronic & Communication Engineering and minored in Data Science at university. My research interests include technologies for human-machine interaction, such as automatic speech recognition, speech synthesis, and natural language processing. I enjoy software development and sometimes like to write my knowledge or thoughts. I want to be helpful to others through open source. You can check my github page (http://github.com/sooftware) to see what I am currently up to.

Education

Kwangwoon University

Seoul, South Korea

MAJOR B.E. IN ELECTRONIC & COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING / MINOR B.E. IN DATA SCIENCE

Mar. 2014 - Feb. 2021 (Expected)

- Major GPA: 3.90 / 4.5 / Total GPA: 3.70 / 4.5
- Courses: Capstone Design I-II, AI & Speech Signal Processing, Software Design, Machine Learning, Computer Architecture, Operating System, Data Structure & Algorithm, Data Mining, Network Programming, IoT System Design, Big Data Language, Big Data Processing & Application, Database, Digital Signal Processing, Statistical application, Object-Oriented Programming, Object-Oriented Programming Practice, Open-Source Software, System Programming, C programming, Mobile Programming, Data Communication, Computer Network, Basic Electronic Circuit Experiment I-II, Electronic Circuit Theory I-II, Digital Logic, Physics Electronic Technology, Engineering Math I-II, Probability and Irregular Signaling Theory, Probability and Statistics

Professional Experience

Kakao Brain Pangyo, Gyunggi

Al Research Engineer

Nov. 2020 - Present

- Research & Develop Speech and Natural Language Processing fields
- Develop Natural Language Processing toolkit used to conduct various NLP tasks (e.g. ASR, NMT, TTS, ..., etc.)

Kakao Brain Pangyo, Gyunggi

RESEARCH INTERNSHIP Aug. 2020 - Nov. 2020

- Research & Develop English, Korean and Chinese Automatic Speech Recognition models
- Development of Multilingual Speech Synthesis Model with Support for 10 Languages

Spoken Language Lab @ Sogang Univ

Mapo, Seoul

Apr. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- Undergraduate Researcher
- Research End-to-End Automatic Speech Recognition Models
 Research Real-time Automatic Speech Recognition Based on Kaldi Toolkit

Research Interests

Speech Speech Recognition, Speech Synthesis, Voice Activity Detection, Speech Enhancement

NLP Machine Translation, Language Model, Cross-lingual

Software Software Architecture, Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structure, Algorithm

Skills

Programming Python, Java, C/C++, Shell Script, SQL, Android, Arduino, Assembly, HTML

Deep Learning PyTorch, Fairseq, PyTorch Lightning, Tensorflow, Keras

Data Analysis Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, BeautifulSoup, Selenium, NLTK

Publication

2020 End-to-End Speech Recognition Models in English, Korean and Chinese, Bachelor's Graduation Thesis

2020 KoSpeech: Open-Source Toolkit for End-to-End Korean Speech Recognition, arXiv pre-print

November 18, 2020 Soohwan Kim · Résumé

Project Experience

Multilingual Speech Synthesis

REPRESENTATIVE

AUTHOR

Kakao Brain

Oct. 2020 - Nov. 2020

REPRESENTATIVE

• Development of a speech synthesis model that supports 10 languages

• Supports for Voice-Cloning and Code-Switching

English, Korean and Chinese ASR Models Development

Kakao Brain

Aug. 2020 - Oct. 2020

• Development of English, Korean and Chinese Wav2vec 2.0 Models

- Experiment for improving the speed of inference
- · Comparative experiment on accuracy / inference speed by output-unit such as Character, Grapheme and Subword

KoSpeech: Open-Source Toolkit for End-to-End Korean Speech Recognition

Kwangwoon University

Jan. 2020 - Aug. 2020

• Currently, over 100 people are stargazer this project [link]

• Write Technical Reports in arXiv [link]

Extracurricular Activity

NLP Paper Reading Kakao Brain

Sep. 2020 - Present **GROUP MEMBER**

- Kakao Brain Natural Language Processing Team's weekly paper reading study
- Reading a paper and summarizing its contents [link]

Technical Blog Naver Blog

WRITER Aug. 2018 - Present

- Technical posting of deep learning, programming, signal processing, paper review etc.
- Having more than 100 subscribers and an average of 200 visitors a day [link]

Speech Recognition Study Group

Kwanawoon University

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2020

• Study speech signal processing (Spectrogram, Mel-Scale, MFCC etc ..)

- Reading a paper of speech recognition and recording its contents [link]

Teaching Experience

Samsung AI Expert Course - Speech recognition

Spoken Language Lab

TEACHING ASSISTANT

GROUP MEMBER

· Conducted Teaching Assistant role in the Speech Recognition session

Jul. 2020 - Aug. 2020

Object-Oriented Programming Practice

Kwangwoon University

Mar. 2020 - Jun. 2020

TEACHING ASSISTANT

- · Covered basic JAVA programming, Ran laboratories and had office hours every week.
- Answered students' questions in person and marked assignments

Awards & Honors

AWARDS

2020.11 1st Place, People's Choice Award. Kwangwoon Engineering Festival (Presider	II S AWarm

2019.10 Finalist (12th Place), Naver A.I Hackathon - Speech

2019.09 Finalist, Kwangwoon University software start-up idea contest - Fall

2019.04 People's Choice Award, Kwangwoon University software start-up idea contest - Spring

2018.08 Best Award, Samsung Multi-Campus in Java-based Algorithm for SW Development

Honors

- 2020.03 School Representative, 5G-based ICT Convergence Service Idea Contest
- 2020.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship
- 2019.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship
- 2019.03 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University
- 2018.09 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University
- 2018.03 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University

SOOHWAN KIM · RÉSUMÉ NOVEMBER 18, 2020